SUBHAM BHATTACHARYA

Personal

Address

O-54, Diamond District, Old Airport Road, Bangalore - 560008 560008 Bangalore

Phone number +91 9538822451

Email subhamhere@gmail.com

Possess over 12 years of extensive experience in Application Development, Training, and operation management.

Experience in leading a team for the successful delivery of challenging projects.

Expertise in Java and Java-related frameworks (Struts, JSF, RichFaces, Spring, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Data Structure).

Experience in developing applications using big data technologies (**Hadoop, Spark, Scala**) Extensive experience in NoSql system (Cassandra, CouchBase, Elastic Search) Associated with *Tesco, SDE-3.*

Experience developing Core Java and J2EE application and providing support in related fields.

Work experience

SDE - 3

Jan 2020 - Present

Tesco, Bangalore

Acting as the Tech Owner of multiple teams, responsible for HLD, LLD and Data Modelling for those teams. I am also responsible for delivering the final product to the production and making sure all the quality factors are met throughout the development and implementation.

Associate Mar 2016 - Jan 2020

JP Morgan Chase, Bangalore

As a tech lead technology team we needed to develop an application that provides automated tax calculation and booking for different jurisdictions.

Accomplishments

Played lead role while designing the data models and

Coming up with an approach and architecture to build a system that can be self-healing and fault-tolerant system.

Gathered knowledge of the business aspect of the system and existing accounting system to become an SME in that matter.

Played the role of tech lead which involves hiring and mentoring junior members of the team. r Instrumental in designing and coding every component of the application.

Associate

Sep 2013 - Mar 2016

Goldman Sachs, Bangalore

As part of the compliance technology team, we needed to develop surveillance to run on and year's worth of data (16 million records). We built a new Hadoop infrastructure and employed technologies like Spark, Scala to deliver the project in only 6 months.

Intermediate Developer

Jan 2012 - Sep 2013

ANZ, Bangalore

The organization being one of the largest banks in the APAC region, the application is used for processing the personal loan application of the customers. Initially, the application was developed using ASP, but due to high cost and other issues related to the maintenance of the application, it decided to be migrated to JSF 2.0. The main business logic resides in AS/400 systems with which the application interacts with the IBM request broker. The team was new in using JSF technology which was the initial challenge and with very limited support from AS/400 teams the integration turned out to be a very challenging task. As a lead developer of the team, I was involved in gathering the requirements, core development, code review, and making the integration possible.

IT Analyst

Mar 2011 - Jan 2012

Tata Consultancy Services, Bangalore

The client being the one of largest financial service providers in the world, the tool is used to obtain the credit history of the individual or an organization. The tool (InterConnect) is used for making decisions on a different financial product based on the credit report. As a member of the fulfillment team, it was our responsibility to customize the tool/product for different clients to meet their business needs.

Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2009 - Feb 2011

Accenture, Bangalore

The client being one of the largest insurance companies in the world, the tool is used for developing insurance products of different categories of insurance that will be sold to the end customer. The tool was initially developed using VB 6. The job involves developing the tool using Java technology and java related frameworks. The development process followed the AGILE methodology for the development which involves delivering codes in three-week Sprints following the development guideline laid down by the client. As a lead developer of the team, I was involved in the core development, code review, and providing technical supports to my team members. Additionally, I help the responsibility of the POC (Point of Contact) for the client.

NIIT Certified Trainer

Mar 2008 - Nov 2009

NIIT Ltd, Kolkata

Imparting training to corporate clients and students on various programming languages and technology with a special focus on Java and J2EE and related technology.

Achieving the highest level of customer satisfaction by providing in-depth knowledge on the subject matter and providing effective and flawless support for business solutions.

Providing effective grooming and hands-on training through real-life projects to students on Core Java and J2EE-related technology so that students become industry-ready for mentioned technology.

Monitoring the performance of students to ensure efficiency in operations and meeting of KRAs.

Computer Instructor

Mar 2004 - Mar 2008

Kalyan Nagar Vidyapith, Kolkata

Acted as a lead developer in the development of a school management product which was responsible to handle all the operations of a school. The product included modules to manage financial matters, human resource-related matters, and daily operation-related matters. I was responsible in building the initial POC and design the system as a distributed application. I was also involved in the transition of the product to an open source platform.

Certified Trainer

Mar 2003 - Feb 2004

NIIT New Alipore, Kolkata

Imparting training to students on various programming languages and technology with a special focus on Java and J2EE and related technology.

Achieving the highest level of customer satisfaction by providing in-depth knowledge on the subject matter.

Monitoring the performance of students to ensure efficiency in operations and meeting of KRAs.

Education and Qualifications

Masters of Computer Science

Jul 2004 - Jul 2012

ICFAI University, Kolkata

B.ScUniversity of Calcutta, Kolkata

Mar 1997 - Mar 2000

Skills

Java	••••
Big Data & Hadoop	••••
Kafka	••••
Cassandra	••••
Elastic Search	••••
Spark	••••